<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carlos Lordelo</title>
    <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Carlos Lordelo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cpvlordelo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Tap &amp; Fiddle&#39; Music Dataset</title>
      <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/projects/tap-and-fiddle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/projects/tap-and-fiddle/</guid>
      <description>In this project we have curated 28 stereo recordings of traditional Scandinavian fiddle tunes with accompanying foot-tapping, which is standard performance practice within these musical styles. Its corpora contains not only the mixed signals, but also the two isolated instrumental tracks that can be used to train supervised models for source separation.
 The fiddle (or violin) track (harmonic); The foot-tapping track (percussive).  Moreover, foot-tapping in performance of fiddle music has not been systematically studied yet, even though it very often appears as an integral part of the musical expression in Scandinavian fiddle music as a percussive accompaniment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Removal of Music Tracks from TV Programmes</title>
      <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/projects/automatic-musictrack-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/projects/automatic-musictrack-removal/</guid>
      <description>This project is related to the research I performed for my Master&amp;rsquo;s Degree. It consists of a method to automatically detect and remove musical segments from TV programme signals. The main idea behind the method is to use a pre-existant music recording, easily obtainable from officially published CDs related to the audiovisual piece, as a reference for the undesired signal.
However, it is important to note that even though we have access to a reference for the music signal we want to extract from the mixture, we do not know the exact segments that appear in the mixture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Harmonic Source Separation</title>
      <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/projects/unsup_harm_source_separation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/projects/unsup_harm_source_separation/</guid>
      <description>I have done this project for my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s Degree thesis. It consists of my own implementation in MATLAB of the algorithm for unsupervised source separation based on the concept of Average Harmonic Structure (AHS) modelling that has been proposed on the following paper:
 Z. Duan, Y. Zhang, C. Zhang and Z. Shi, &amp;ldquo;Unsupervised Single-Channel Music Source Separation by Average Harmonic Structure Modeling&amp;rdquo;, in IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech, and Language Processing, vol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grants &amp; Awards</title>
      <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/awards/</guid>
      <description>  Marie Sklodowska-Curie Action (MSCA) Fellowship for PhD Programme in Computer Science at Queen Mary University of London (QMUL), UK, 2018-2021 - MIP-Frontiers Project
  Brazilian Science Without Borders Scholarship for Exchange Study Period at University of California, Berkeley, USA 2013-2014
  Honourable Mention for the performance in the Mathematics Olympiads of the State of Rio de Janeiro &amp;ndash; OMERJ, Brazil, 2009
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I am a researcher at Doremir Music Research AB and a PhD student in Computer Science at the Centre For Digital Music (C4DM) at the Queen Mary University of London (QMUL). I currently hold a Marie Sklodowska Curie scholarship and am part of the MIP-Frontiers project, where I am the student responsible for the QMUL2 research project. Previously, I received a MSc degree in Electrical Engineering from the Federal University of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (UFRJ) and BSc was in Electronic and Computer Engineering from the same university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Here is a list of my publications by year.
Note: PDF is for personal use only. Copyrights are reserved by Publishers
2021   C. Lordelo, E. Benetos, S. Dixon and S. Ahlbäck, &amp;ldquo;Pitch-informed instrument streaming &amp;quot; in International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR), October 2021. [pdf]
  C. Lordelo, E. Benetos, S. Dixon, S. Ahlbäck and P. Ohlsson, &amp;ldquo;Adversarial Unsupervised Domain Adaptation for Harmonic-Percussive Source Separation&amp;rdquo;, in IEEE Signal Processing Letters, vol.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
