<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carlos Lordelo</title>
    <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Carlos Lordelo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Base de dados de Música &#34;Tap &amp; Fiddle&#34;</title>
      <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/projects/tap-and-fiddle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/projects/tap-and-fiddle/</guid>
      <description>[VERSÃO EM PORTUGUÊS EM CONSTRUÇÃO. A SEGUIR SEGUE A VERSÃO EM INGLÊS]
In this project we have curated 28 stereo recordings of traditional Scandinavian fiddle tunes with accompanying foot-tapping, which is standard performance practice within these musical styles. Its corpora contains not only the mixed signals, but also the two isolated instrumental tracks that can be used to train supervised models for source separation.
 The fiddle (or violin) track (harmonic); The foot-tapping track (percussive).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remoção Automática de Trilha Musical de Programas de TV</title>
      <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/projects/automatic-musictrack-removal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/projects/automatic-musictrack-removal/</guid>
      <description>[VERSÃO EM PORTUGUÊS EM CONSTRUÇÃO. A SEGUIR SEGUE A VERSÃO EM INGLÊS]
This project is related to the research I performed for my Master&amp;rsquo;s Degree. It consists of a method to automatically detect and remove musical segments from TV programme signals. The main idea behind the method is to use a pre-existant music recording, easily obtainable from officially published CDs related to the audiovisual piece, as a reference for the undesired signal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Separação Não-Supervisionada de Fontes Harmônicas</title>
      <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/projects/unsup_harm_source_separation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/projects/unsup_harm_source_separation/</guid>
      <description>[VERSÃO EM PORTUGUÊS EM CONSTRUÇÃO. A SEGUIR SEGUE A VERSÃO EM INGLÊS]
I have done this project for my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s Degree thesis. It consists of my own implementation in MATLAB of the algorithm for unsupervised source separation based on the concept of Average Harmonic Structure (AHS) modelling that has been proposed on the following paper:
 Z. Duan, Y. Zhang, C. Zhang and Z. Shi, &amp;ldquo;Unsupervised Single-Channel Music Source Separation by Average Harmonic Structure Modeling&amp;rdquo;, in IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech, and Language Processing, vol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bolsas e Prêmios</title>
      <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/awards/</guid>
      <description>  Bolsa de estudos Marie Sklodowska-Curie Action (MSCA) para Programa de PhD em Ciência da Computação na Queen Mary University of London (QMUL), Reino Unido, 2018-2021 - Projeto MIP-Frontiers
  Bolsa de estudos Ciência sem Fronteiras para Intercâmbio acadêmico na Universidade da California, Berkeley, EUA 2013-2014
  Menção Honrosa pelo desempenho nas Olimpíadas de Matemática do Estado do Rio de Janeiro &amp;ndash; OMERJ, Brasil, 2009
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sobre Mim</title>
      <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/about/</guid>
      <description>Oi, eu sou um pesquisador na Doremir Music Research AB e aluno de PhD em Ciência da Computação no Centre For Digital Music (C4DM) na Queen Mary University of London (QMUL). Atualmente possuo uma bolsa Marie Sklodowska Curie e sou parte do projeto MIP-Frontiers, onde sou o aluno responsável pelo projeto de pesquisa QMUL2. Anteriormente, recebi meu diploma de Mestrado em Engenharia Elétrica pela Universidade Federal do Rio de Janeiro (UFRJ) em 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publicações</title>
      <link>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cpvlordelo.github.io/pt-br/publications/</guid>
      <description>Aqui está uma lista das minhas publicações por ano.
Nota: Os PDFs são apenas para uso pessoal. Direitos autorais são reservados pelas editoras
2021   C. Lordelo, E. Benetos, S. Dixon e S. Ahlbäck, &amp;ldquo;Pitch-informed instrument streaming &amp;quot; in International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR), Outubro 2021. [pdf]
  C. Lordelo, E. Benetos, S. Dixon, S. Ahlbäck e P. Ohlsson, &amp;ldquo;Adversarial Unsupervised Domain Adaptation for Harmonic-Percussive Source Separation&amp;rdquo;, em IEEE Signal Processing Letters, vol.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
